Kusum Thapa

11 Glebe Road, Colchester, CO2 9LP

Email: <u>kusumthapa_magar@hotmail.com</u>
Mob no. 07575813945

Profile

Highly motivated, enthusiastic and hardworking graduate software developer with more than 3 years of experience on MIS software development field. Technically proficient with sound knowledge of software technologies especially in ASP.net programming and data management. Good interpersonal skills and a great team attitude with an ability to deal with all clients at all levels of the business. Acquire a valid DBS clearance certificate. After a career break in programming due to parental commitment looking to secure a software developer role with an established company where I can utilise and further develop my skills and aid company growth.

Employment History

Jul 2019 - Present Achievements:

Global Escapes Ltd, Online Travel Consultant - Self-Employed (Part-time) Colchester, UK

- Effectively planning, organising and managing the daily aspects of running company by looking after operational, financial and administrative duties.
- Promoting, marketing and managing holidays packages and travel arrangement for clients and providing them excellent customer services.
- Involved in three-months project contracted by Hays Travel and successfully worked as a COVID 19 Vulnerable People Advisor. Efficiently provided service by making outbound calls to extremely medically vulnerable people help people receive basic supplies of food, medicine and in some cases referring them to their local authority due to desperately needing help to in some case referring them to emergency services for immediate care.
 - Successfully created trust by engaging in meaningful interactions, actively listening and capturing the essential data to register them into government portal for any support.

Jun 2016 - Sep 2017 Achievements:

System Data Manager, Ayios Nikolaos Primary School

Cyprus

- Effectively record, analysed, presented and managed pupil, staff and school's data on IntegrsG2(RM Education) MIS system.
- Provided direct assistant to Head teacher for data and assessment. Ensured all the data in the school were accurate and up to date and provided relevant reports for students and parents and analysis for Senior Leaders.
- Managed the admissions process for prospective pupils effectively responding to all the enquiries and providing welcoming response to any enquiries concerning pupil admissions.

Nov 2012 – Oct 2015

Software Consultant/ Developer, Furlong Business Solutions

Andover, UK

Achievements:

- Gained experience on designing and developing desktop and web solutions for school-based data management system using MVC framework in ASP.Net programming language.
- Managed projects for data transfer for local and international schools. Communicated well and
 dealt with the school data managers to understand their school's pupil and staff data structure and
 their old system. Achieved positive feedbacks from clients for providing them technical support
 for using our system and completing the project before the deadlines.
- Successfully completed numerous development assignments which required meeting with clients
 to gather specific requirements, designing, implementing, testing, bug fixing and providing
 technical assistance of the new product.

Jun 2010 -Jun 2011

Junior Software Developer, Staffordshire County Council

Stafford, UK

- Achievements:
 Ability to care customers better, and meet business needs and customer expectations
 - Work together person to person; team to team and service to service within the County Council.
 - Develop theoretical skills by applying them in the real practical world.
 - Knowledge of different hardware and software technologies used in council to achieve the objectives of business.
 - Experience gained on SAP BI, web application development using .NET framework and desktop application using Java.

Volunteering

Jan 2020 - Present

Child Workforce Community Support Worker

Colchester, UK

Achievements:

 Opportunity to provide support for young children by involving in running youth for their personal and social development

Sep2012 – Nov 2012 Achievements: IT Buddies, Andover Neighbour Care Silver Surfer Internet Café

Andover, UK

 Developed good communication skills with elderly customers and getting their positive feedbacks for my assistance they received during the course.

Jan 2011 – Jun 2012 Achievements: IT Buddies, Stafford Library

Stafford, UK

Opportunity to interact with different peoples and share basic knowledge of IT with them.
Sharing experiences and offer support to the basic learners creating a friendly environment.

Education

Sep-2008 – Jul 2012 Dissertation BSc (Hons) Computing Science (2:1), Staffordshire University A Prototype Enterprise Student Timetabling System Stafford, UK

A prototype web-based application with Java EE, developed for students, enabling them to visualise and integrate their selected module's timetable into a clash-free master timetable. The application data synchronises with the live university timetable information system and notifies student of any changes in their subscribed master timetable.

Achievements

The Final year project won the first place in GradEx 2012 from the category of Computing and Information Systems. Gradex is an annual exhibition of final year projects of students in Faculty of Computing, Engineering and Technology.

Relevant Modules

Algorithm and Data structure in C, Object oriented programming, System Modelling, Introduction to operating system, Further Object Oriented Programming, Further Programming C++, Database Systems, Current Programming in C#, Principle and Practises of Software Production, Graphical User Interface: Design and Implementation, Software Development for mobile computing, Algorithms, Design Patterns, Enterprise Application with Java Enterprise Edition, Advanced Programming language concepts, Project Management

2006 – 2007 Relevant Modules BEng (Hons) Computer Engineering (1st Year), Kantipur Engineering College

Nepal
Computer Programming, I Practical (96), Physics Practical (92), Electric Circuits I Practical (90),

Mathematics II (85), Communication (English) (85)

2004 – 2006 Science (Intermediate level equivalent to A levels), United Academy

Nepal

Mathematics (70), English (70), Chemistry (71), Physics (70)

1990 – 2003 School Leaving Certificate (SLC Equivalent to GCSE), Future Stars High School

Nepal

Key Skills and Achievements

Technical Skills

Programming Languages:	ASP.Net, C#, VB.Net, Java, T-SQL
IDE:	Visual Studio Enterprise / TFS 2008/2012/2017/2019; NetBeans; SQL Server Studio; Visio
Web Technologies:	LINQ, JavaScript, JSON, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, XML, J2EE, AJAX, Web Services, Azure
Framework:	MVC, Entity Framework, LINQ to SQL
Development	Agile Development, UML Diagram
Methodologies:	
Version Control:	Team Foundation Server(TFS), GIT, GITHub
Exams:	MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional (2013); MS: Programming in HTML5 with
	JavaScript and CSS3 Specialist (2013); Level 2 ECDL certificate from BCS

References References available upon request